Omkar Savalkar

Front End Developer

Computer Software Engineer having strong work experience of 1.6 years as Front end developer with proven quick learning, best performing and team player ability. Have knowledge of working on web application development projects from scratch using frontend react skills during job tenure and seeking for more opportunitities in a reputed firm.

Website:- https://omkar-ownwebapp.vercel.app

EXPERIENCE

Xoriant Solutions Pvt. Ltd (Product-Service), Pune, Maharashtra **Software Engineer**

August 2021 - Present

- Contributed and developed client project's UI code from scratch using React, Typescript and Material UI.
- Responsible for integrating 40% Rest API's involved with the front end.
- Presented and demonstrated 5 successful workflow demos to clients.
- Worked on debugging, code bug fixes and resolving code issues.
- Implemented enhancements at later stages in less span as per requirement.
- Attended client meetings, tested application, took complete responsibility by quickly delivering requirements along with continuous learning.

INTERNSHIP

HealByUs Healthcare, Pune, Maharashtra *Android Developer Intern*

June 2020 - Aug 2020

- Worked on a complete project and actively contributed in planning, UI design, development and testing with the team.
- <u>Tech Stack</u> Android Studio, Core-Java, Firebase.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Connect Well (dynamic web application), Hackathon Project *Fullstack Developer*

November 2022 - January 2022

- Contributed in complete SDLC and majorly on coding of web application that can be integrated with company's portal.
- <u>Tech Stack</u> React Js, TypeScript, Material UI, Redux, Next Js, Node Js, MongoDB and other libraries.

Portfolio (React web application), Remote

- Developed eye catching user friendly interface covering all required features for displaying my complete details.
- <u>Tech Stack</u> React Js, JavaScript, SASS / CSS, Styled-Components.

Address:- Pune, Maharashtra,

India, 411062

Mobile No:- +91-9766112890

Email:-

omkarsavalkar22@gmail.com

Linkedin:-

https://www.linkedin.com/in

/omkar-savalkar

Github profile:-

https://github.com/OmkarSa valkar

SKILLS

React

Javascript

Typescript

Material UI

Redux

Next Js

HTML - CSS

Node Js

Git

Visual Studio Code

EDUCATION

Nutan Maharashtra Institute of Engineering and Technology

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

June 2021

Pune, Maharashtra

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Achieved Xoriant Spot Award for Best Performance in team (Xoriant Solutions).
- 1st prize for Final Year
 Project in (UGCON) 2021